Marlon Maniti

Front-End Developer / UI/UX Designer

address mobile email web One Tree Hill, Auckland 1061 +64 22 354 3442 lonmaniti@gmail.com nolrm.github.io

summary

I am a perfectionist with a real passion for design and development on the web. I specialize in creating attractive, accessible, fun and friendly websites built upon a solid foundation of semantic markup, placing great importance on the latest web standards.

technical expertise

Professional Skillset

- W3C Validated HTML5
- CSS3 via SASS & Compass, Less, SCSS
- Twitter Bootstrap
- ¡Query, JavaScript
- Website optimization + cross browser capabilities
- Responsive Design

Working Knowledge

- AngularJS, AJAX, JSON
- Jekyll, Grunt
- CMS (WordPress, Joomla, Magento)
- Velocity Templating (Server-side)

Tools

- SublimeText2
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Github
- Invision

employment

Red Box Front-End Developer / Magento Developer Auckland, New Zealand (Nov 2015 - Present)

Developing Ecommerce website using Magento 2.0

Trust Codes Limited Front-End Developer (Freelance) Auckland, New Zealand (Nov 2015 - Present)

Developing mobile application using latest front-end technologies.

TORO.IO Front-End Developer / Web Designer Philippines (May 2014 - July 2015)

Software development company that focused on producing on his own CMS with web application development tool.

 Created default widgets using Velocity Template(server-side templating) from the e-commerce API

employment

- Scaffold the project to setup the needed build tools for the project (using npm and bower)
- Created UI-Kit Styleguide to be use for the TORO apps
- Design website, logo, icons and etc.
- Collaborated with Front-end and Back-end Developers for TORO tools improvement.
- Guides and act as a mentor to Front-end OJTs. Check and Review the OJTs codes, if they follow the basic coding standards for front-end development.

Huchcode Junior Web Designer (June 2012 - May 2014)

Game development company partnered with Game on (Korea-Japan).

- Converts PSD to HTML5/CSS3(Smartphone and Feature Phone)
- Develop clean, valid(W3C), Responsive and Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Converted Flash to Google Swiffy/Create JS
- Created simple HTML5/JS using Adobe Edge
- Backend Templating (PHP)
- Design website, logo and other marketing materials.

Freelance (Feb 2012 - Present)

- Created responsive website and sometimes using CMS
- Designed website and logo

Advantpoint Inc. Web Designer (Sept 2011 - Feb 2012)

- Created website using Vivvo CMS and maintained company website
- Designed website and other marketing materials
- Troubleshooting PCs / Assist technical support

Metaverse Services Ltd. Online Game Support (Sept 2010 - Sept 2011)

Designed banner, logos and other marketing materials. Advertised company on different advertising websites.

Mass Communication Studio On-the-job Trainee (Nov 2009 - Mar 2010)

Serves as Graphic Artist(Layout Brochure and other Marketing Materials). Design Title Cards for Maski Nanu TV Show. Answer phone calls and perform other administrative function, as it may be necessary.

education

Holy Angel University, Angeles City, Philippines Received a **Bachelor of Science** in Information Technology Major in Multimedia during April 2010.

References and code samples available upon request.

nolrm.github.io
lonmaniti@gmail.com